RG 004:072, Ledyard Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Ledyard Probate Court records
1837-1934
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Ledyard District)
25.25 cubic feet
Record books, 1837-1957; Probate files, 1837-1972.
RG004_072
1923-004, 2011-068, 2011-069
Historical Note
Ledyard, New London County, Town established in June 1836, Parent Town: Groton
The Ledyard Probate District was constituted June 6, 1837, from the Stonington Probate District. The Ledyard Probate District merged with Groton, North Stonington, and North Stonington Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Southeastern Corner Regional Probate District which serves the municipalities of Groton, Ledyard, North Stonington, and Stonington.
Town of Ledyard, Probate District chronology:
May 1836 - June 5, 1837, Stonington District
June 6, 1837 - January 4, 2011, Ledyard District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Southeastern Corner Regional District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1837-1957. Includes records/wills and inventories, volumes 1-6, and journals/orders and decrees, volumes 1-6. There is also one bond volume. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume 6.
Probate files, 1833-1976. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. Includes a small number of files from the New Haven Probate District that pre-date the creation of the Bethany Probate District in 1854. Most of these files are for incompetency cases.
Inventory control book, 1833-1950 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Volumes of "records" are numbered 1 to 3 and continued by volumes of "wills and inventories" numbered 4 to 6. Volumes of "journals" are numbered 1 to 3 and continued by "orders and decrees" numbered 4 and 6. Orders and decrees, Volume 5, was not transferred to the Connecticut State Library.
Probate files are arranged by accession. Each accession is arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in accession 1923-004 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-069.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut - Ledyard
Places:
Ledyard (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1972 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Accession 2011-068, Record books, 1837-1957; and Accession 2011-069, Probate files, 1908-1972, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 1-4, records/wills and inventories, 1837-1923, and Volume 1, Jouranl, 1837-1857; probate files 1837-1915 (Accession 1923-004 only); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1923-004 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): October 23, 1923 (1837-1920); April 25, 1958 (1855-1934). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
The record books in accession 2011-068 and the probate files in accession 2011-069 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on December 13, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1837-1957; 8.5 cubic feet (23 volumes); 2011-068
  - Records, 1837-1859 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1859-1879 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1879-1893 (Volume 3)
  - Wills and inventories, 1893-1906 (Volume 4)
  - Wills and inventories, 1906-1923 (Volume 5)
  - Wills and inventories, 1922-1947 (Volume 6)
  - Journal, 1837-1857 (Volume 1)
  - Journal, 1858-1875 (Volume 2)
  - Journal, 1875-1893 (Volume 3)
  - Orders and decrees, 1894-1914 (Volume 4)
  - Orders and decrees, 1914-1957 (Volume 6)
  - Bonds, 1881-1924 (Volume unnumbered)
- Index cards, .5 cubic feet; 2011-068
  - Index cards (Box 1)
    Index cards to the record books
- Probate files, 1837-1934; 3.25 cubic feet; 1923-004
  - Adams - Chapman, L. (Drawer 1)
  - Chapman, M. - Lester, N. (Drawer 2)
  - Lester, O. - Smith (Drawer 3)
  - Spicer - Z.; Miscellaneous (Drawer 4)
- Inventory Control Book, 1837-1934; T003073
  Index of the two accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1923-004
  Date span is coverage
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, 1837-1934; 3.25 cubic feet; 2011-069
  - Abbott - Bayless (Box 1)
  - Bence - Clark, A. (Box 2)
  - Clark, H. - Diedrich (Box 3)
  - DiMascola - Gore (Box 4)
  - Goulart - Herbert (Box 5)
  - Hewes - Kelly (Box 6)
  - Kennedy - Lynn (Box 7)
  - McCary - Moran (Box 8)
  - Morgan - Peckham (Box 9)
  - Peliter - Schafer (Box 10)
  - Sheldon - Watkins (Box 11)
  - Watrous - Zimet (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 13)